A Guide to the W. E. Bugg journals and papers, 1858-1977
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
W. E. Bugg journals and papers, 1858-1977
The Library of Virginia
41194
1.8 cubic feet and 4 boxes
W. E. Bugg
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor information unavailable
Alternative Form Available
Journals of William Emmanuel Bugg, 1848-1935: Mecklenburg County, Virginia, and Warren County, North Carolina, with Bugg, Davis, Hudgins, Nicholson, Smith, Walker.
Biographical Information
William Emmanuel Bugg was born in Mecklenburg County, Virginia, and attended school there. He moved to Warren County, North Carolina, in 1870. He worked on his uncle John Askew's farm and also taught school for a few years. Bugg farmed in Warren County for many years before returning to Mecklenburg County to live with his daughter's family. Bugg married Mary Ella Smith (d. 1925) 1 March 1883 and they had ten children, nine of whom lived to adulthood. Bugg died April 1935 in Mecklenburg County.
Scope and Content
Journals and papers, 1858-1977, of W. E. Bugg (1848-1935) of Mecklenburg County, Virginia, and Warren County, North Carolina, consisting of account books, cemetery records, clippings, copy books, correspondence, diaries, genealogical notes, memorandum books, notebooks, poems, scrapbooks and other papers, detailing Bugg's life and his activities as a farmer and teacher, as well as providing information on the communities in which he lived. Journals include account books of John Askew of Warren County and an unidentified partial account book from Pennsylvania. Papers contain personal and family correspondence, genealogical notes, notes on religion, receipts, and newspaper clippings.
Contents List
- Account book and copy book, 1858, 1867-1868 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Diary, 1871-1874 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Account book, 1872-1874 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Account book and diary, 1872-1875 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Account book, 1872-1875, 1891-1901 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Diary, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Account book, 1875-1880 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Memoranda book, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Account book, 1885-1889, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Account book, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Account book, 1902-1906 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Account book, 1906-1908 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Account book, 1907-1918 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Account book, 1908-1914 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Diary and notebook, 1918-1935 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Diary and account book, 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Account book, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Account book and diary, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Diary and scrapbook, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Diary and notebook, 1925-1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Diary, 1928-1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Diary, 1929-1934 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Memorandum book, 1930-1933 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Diary and notebook, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook (accounts), 1931-1935 (ca. 1920-1922) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Diary, 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Acount book, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Notebook and pouch, no date (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Check register, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Loose journal and accounts pages, no date (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Loose scrapbook pages, no date (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook section, no date (Box 4, Folder 3)
- New Testament (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Bible Briefs Against Hurtful Heresies (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Deed, 21 September 1896 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Papers, 1911, 1917, 1919[?] (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Papers, 1920-1929 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Papers, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Papers, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Papers, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Papers, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Papers, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Papers, 1962, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Papers: correspondence, no date (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Papers: genealogical notes, no date (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Papers: miscellaneous, no date (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Newspaper clippings, no date (Box 4, Folder 18)